we will say no to people even if their
coding and system design is good this
guy was a principal engineer at Amazon
he conducted thousands of interviews
while he was there and last month I went
to his Studio to ask him to teach me
everything he knows about interviewing
in big Tech he also shared a ton of
unexpected stories H from his promotion
to principal engineer at Amazon how many
people are expected to be cut in Amazon
typically what I can say
is the PIP or performance Improvement
plan and then what about the worst
manager you had yeah I don't want to
name names or anything
but I know that you came from a liberal
arts background um your major going into
college was actually English right yeah
I was creative writing and and English
literature so can you tell us a little
bit about you getting into Amazon
without a CS major yeah I think um just
getting in as a liberal arts major may
be a bit disingenuous uh both of my
parents were electrical engineers and so
I've always had a computer around the
house and um you know I used to program
that computer I still remember my first
one it was an uh IBM XT
8088 with uh 640k of ram no hard disk
two five and two five and a qu uh two 5
and a qu inch floppy discs so that it's
a floppy disc that's actually floppy not
the hard one that you you probably don't
even remember um and so you know I've
I've always been been coding and uh
since a really young age in high school
I did the computer science uh AP tests
my sophomore year I did the ab test
which was in Pascal way back when Pascal
is a programming language and um my
junior year uh it was in C++ and I did
the BC test and so I knew about the
concepts of you know Big O um algorithms
and data structures how to write
programs you know I still remember
making like a Tetris clone when I was in
high school so you know the fact that I
broke in without a computer science
degree if you just said the part about
the English degree um like I said it's a
it's a bit disingenuous and so I I went
to school I got a liberal arts degree I
did get a minor um in math and applied
math and I took some computer science
courses you know when I when I got out
of school I
I was looking for work and it was around
2005 2006 I still remember this story I
went and talked to my my writing
Professor uh in one of my senior year
seminars at udub and I was like
Professor bossworth like what type of
job should I get um I want to be a
writer and he said he put his hand on my
shoulder and he was like Steve there's
no job called writer it's it's like not
not yet there is a job called waiter and
so you just have to find a way to sort
of support
yourself um while you ply your craft
right and so just finding some sort of
way to eek by while you get some
experience under your belt I wasn't
really turned on by that and so I
decided to to revisit the skills that I
picked up in high school and before that
I see so I mean to me then it is
disingenuous to say that as if you came
from zero skill but your
resume came from zero is my
understanding right because if if you
look if I was a big tech recruiter and I
was looking through stack of resumés and
English major comes
along you probably would not stand out
when it comes to you know the the job
market so what is the thing that you did
that got you into Amazon it was through
networking so somebody that I did AP
Computer Science with work at Amazon he
went to University of Washington and got
a proper computer science degree and was
a software developer at Amazon and so
they needed some support Engineers uh
and it was a contract position and so I
basically was like can you get me an
interview at the company and I was just
I was not worried about a coding
interview because of my prior experience
but also you know I think with support
engineers they writing scripts and and
maintaining systems and so I got through
on that interview and um you know I was
a green badge contractor for about nine
months before I transitioned a fulltime
what's green badge mean just temp yeah
it's a temp I see it's an Amazon term
yeah so the blue badge would be
full-time and then green badge is a
contractor yellow is like a vendor or
got it got it got it like maybe today's
environment is like a bit more intense
where people want to get into big TCH
and you know Amazon's a big name at this
point but
also your resume although it was not CS
the thing that got you in was that you
knew someone and they gave you like a a
referral and that made a big difference
that at least got you the the interview
and then you had the skills cuz you were
you had been doing CS for a while yeah I
think the way to think about it if you
know when I when I guide people trying
to get a job it takes two things it
takes you know some amount of
opportunity and it takes some amount of
study
and so you don't know when the
opportunity is going to pop up you don't
know if your Uncle Daniel from
church you know will talk to somebody
that knows about a job opening you don't
know when that's going to land it's very
unevenly distributed where these
opportunities come from but I think over
time they will come and and rear their
their heads or make themselves available
I think the other side of it is the
preparedness right so upleveling
yourself gaining knowledge gaining
skills that needs to to occur you can't
just have the opportunity and then not
have the skills right and so those two
need things need to marry and so you
know I think back then it was much more
difficult to gain the knowledge that was
necessary to to get into big Tech today
you know you see all of these cottage
industries around interview prep getting
ready for the coding interview none of
that stuff existed when I was trying to
get in and so I think it would actually
be harder um back then to get your foot
into the door in Tech from a
non-traditional background than it is
today now I won't say that it's
necessarily easy today but at least in
my mind I think it was more difficult
for me yeah I remember when we worked on
that post together you said there wasn't
even the idea of like uh lists of leak
code questions and things and you were
just collecting interview questions to
prepare yeah so when I was uh a support
engineer and I um you know they made me
blue badge so full-time employee but I
just I wanted to be an SD so bad and so
all I did for the audience's software
development engineer yeah and so I
wanted to be a software developer so bad
I just cornered everybody I just became
a collector of questions I was like what
do you ask during interviews and I was
like don't tell me the answer I'm going
to go and figure it out and so you know
just did it the oldfashioned way um just
firing up an IDE and you know you don't
have all these battery of test cases
they get run like you know with Le code
and stuff now and so you know generating
your own test case you know that's
that's a way to sort of uplevel yourself
so I feel like I did it in a just in a
time where you know we weren't so
resourcer so I imagine that probably
lowered the average performance of a of
an
interviewee uh and maybe because you had
some
extraordinary uh process of like
collecting questions that you might have
been like you know very outstanding when
it comes to everyone because ultimately
interview prep is a little bit
competitive you need to be better than
the other people to to get in yes and no
I I think of the distribution of demand
for software developers is skewed I just
especially today I don't think there's a
ton of demand for junior folks I think
there's a extraordinary amount of demand
for senior and above the reality is that
seniors come from mid-level and juniors
and so I think the pipeline is a bit
busted right now I don't necessarily
think of a ton of competition at the
upper end um I do think that there is a
lot at the lower end um but the
competition doesn't exist at the
interview stage I think the competition
exists at the pre-qualification and
selection phase and so if you're able to
catch the attention of a recruiter say
you know somebody that works at the
company or you're able to go really deep
in a particular area and and stand out
maybe you built an app
has some amount of customers that's
where the competition is like you need
to stand out on the selection side by
the time you get to the interview it
like it's just a matter of clearing the
bar there and so you're the the
dimension of competition is not at the
coding level I don't think why do you
think that most interview prep advice is
garbage I think that most interview prep
is
non-optimal and so
you know there's a there's a hyperfocus
on the coding
interview there's a hyperfocus now on
system
design but I think really
people forget they so they they turn it
into a
test and in some sense it is if you
can't code then they they don't want you
um if you can't design a system and
you're a senior like you know it's not
going to work out like if we put you in
a in a role it's it's just you're going
to be that 5% that leave right we don't
want to do that and
so the the big overarching framework is
the people on the other side of the
table are trying to figure out whether
they want to work with you whether
you're going to be a good fit for the
culture but people think about it in
terms of a test and
so it's much more like a date than it is
like at the
sat right and but the but the the prep
industry the interview prep
industry it's much easier to think about
it and present it as a
test right and so I wish people would
just embed this uh you know some things
like hey behavioral interviews have an
outsized impact on whether they're going
to hire you and what level you're going
to come in at so instead of say spending
80% of your time on
coding or maybe let's say 60% on coding
and then 35% on system design and like
the 5% is like the donate to charity pie
slice like maybe it's much more like 40%
40% 20% right because that behavioral
side I think is really where the match
is made where and where behavioral is
the
20% I was a bar Razer trainer and I
trained thousands of people at Amazon on
how to conduct interviews assess talent
and then level people before the
training was you know now it's a set of
videos but it used to be live training
so I've trained many people on this and
what I used to say and I'll say it right
now is the coding so the functional
parts of the interview the coding
interview the system design interview
those things are the anti right so
they're the small blind and big blind so
I use a poker analogy they're the small
blind and big blind of of getting into a
company and
the the behavioral part of the
interview that's the poker part of Poker
right that's like do you have a good
hand you know trying to beat the other
hand of the other person and
so if you thought about the coding part
and the system design part as necessary
but not
sufficient like that's the that's the
thing that I wish people
understood right we will say no to
people that have poor behavioral
answers poor not in the sense that they
don't have the experience it needs it's
just we can recognize from far away that
it's not going to be a good fit for the
company we'll say no to those people
even if their coding and system design
is good you're saying at Amazon it's
like the functional part it's like
coding system that's like pass no pass
yes but once you pass it your leveling
and the I guess the color behind how how
good you are is the behavioral yes I see
okay okay so then what what should
people do to kind of um you prevent from
being down leveled because their
behavioral is bad I think
that they should spend some time on what
I call
packaging so if you can package your
experience and sort of communicate that
packaging to your
interviewer I think that's just optimal
for both sides right so you are
packaging your experience you're you're
communicating to them what you're all
about how you operate what things you've
done in the
past and you can make that a good story
you can not it doesn't have to be
entertaining but it can be efficient and
you can you know if if you are able to
effectively articulate yourself and
communicate it to your
interviewer I think now we're talking
about empathy now we're talking about
things like this is the fundamental
question for interviews is like do I
want to work with this person
that's the question that this whole song
and dance for the for the interview
process is trying to figure out do I
want to work with this person or
not and and I think spending some time
on the behavioral side is about trying
to help the interviewer answer that
question so you are just you're really
trying to act like yourself and and not
you know it's not NE you want to put
your best foot
forward you don't want to lie obviously
you want to misrepresent yourself but I
I really think that um you know just
being able to talk about who you are
what you're about and your experience
like that's the important part that's
the missing part from all of this
Cottage like interview prep that's going
on on the internet that's the big thing
that's missing could you give me an
example of packaging like what maybe you
could package your as if you were going
to sell yourself back and go back to
Tech yeah you know so um just even
something like tell me about yourself
right um I think people people kind of
gloss over that and they kind of run on
sentence their way through it and you
know I think if I were to answer a
question like that it would just be like
hey you know my name is Steve fnn I have
you know I have a a passion for backend
distributed
systems um I really love to work on um
you know customer facing products I'm a
sports fan you know I used to work at
Amazon tickets and and Prime video
sports and um you know I I really love
like building teams and and really you
know taking an organization's
engineering culture and upleveling it at
that level like those are those are some
of my passions right I didn't prep for
that that was kind of a interview off
the cuff but you know hopefully you got
a sense of you know who I am and what
I'm about
and the level that I operate one thing
that I like to say is that the stories
you tell they they sort of betray your
level the way that you you you
communicate with people they betray your
level right and so if you have
stories that are sd1 stories right entry
level stories but you're trying to get a
senior
role that that in congruity is the thing
that's going to lead to the down
leveling yeah that makes sense and like
the last thing that you said there was
upleveling teams you're almost speaking
to like a like a staff or higher rubric
where you know it's not like you said oh
I like to clean up the code or yeah I
love refactoring code it's like I do
yeah but that's not that's not how I'm
going to describe myself yeah right and
so I um trying to turn this into a video
of some sort but I just I want to do a
thing where I just talk with somebody
for five minutes and I try to figure out
whether they're senior or mid or staff
or whatever they are oh that'd be
interesting like a blind yeah yeah like
you don't know and you just yeah and
maybe I'm you know maybe I'm
overconfident but I just I feel like if
I talk to a junior entry-level person I
would know that they're a junior entry
level person they just they just just
the way that they carry themselves the
the things that they talk about you know
um now maybe on the you know if they're
a strong senior
engineer you know are they going to be
able the pass as a principal yeah
there's some there's some places where I
um you know I might struggle but I I
think I'm really calibrated in terms of
level so that's for the interview stage
what about before you get the interview
right now it's a really competitive job
market do you have any advice for people
to stand out you have to be an outlier
in some regard and so being an outlier
May mean oh I have a contact that can
give me a referral to a big tech company
I think that if you just if you C DMD
some folks on a team that had an opening
and it was you know you didn't like spam
them it didn't look like a like a like
an auto DM sort of thing or a script you
didn't sound like Ai and you were just
like hey my name's Ryan um I noticed you
work on this team and you have some
openings like can you tell me what it's
like on your team like what are the sort
of things that you do on a day to-day
basis and then also you know I'm a I'm a
university student I'm about to graduate
in 3 months like how can I position
myself optimally in order to get this
job I I ran a poll on my
Discord and 90% of people said that if
somebody did that and they were genuine
about it that they would interact with
him and that they would actually extend
a referral if they asked right and so
that's a that's an easy way to be an
outlier in networking you know I I think
about a lot you know there's this
networking stuff where it's just like
hey you know strengthen your your
networking go up and talk to people
there's this and it's American style too
so it's like everybody thinks it's fake
and surface level but that's not what
I'm talking about right like you should
do those things but like really like
networking is about making some sort of
connection right and so if you're able
to connect with people they're in a spot
to help you if you can provide value to
them right I think that's the that's one
way to be an outlier I think um if
you're if you're new and you're you're
willing to pick up skills hey what's the
skill that I should pick up so that I'm
much more attractive to to uh big Tech
or to to getting a job I think that most
people should go deep instead of going
broad you know they'll be like Oh I'm
going to
you know I'm doing a react tutorial and
I'm going to learn rusts and then
there's a machine learning python thing
with you know py toch and they go breath
and there's no cohesion there it's like
you know mobile app development and
machine learning yeah you can make them
sort of you know connect to each other
but at some sense it's contrived and
there's just so much to learn and so I I
give the general guidance it's just like
okay well what's the thing that
interests you in a frame work or a
language that you are you like you
already know like how deep can you go in
a particular you know in a thing that
you already have some familiarity with
2025 is there a top programming language
that you'd recommend for someone to go
deep in the cheeky answer is English is
the top programming language in
2025 um what what do you mean by that
you know we had talked about it a little
bit before but the ability to
communicate yourself the ability to
package your experience and tell a good
story I think that's the thing that's
going that's the high leverage activity
um in terms of languages you know dude
I've been I've been programming you know
I I've done assembly in basic and Pascal
and c and C+ like I learned c c in 1990
right like languages
are they come and they go like I I'm I
consider myself a pearl expert like that
that's no longer useful right and so
like the language itself I think in a
sense is immaterial I think this is
where I think you know your your
personal curiosity like it's totally
fine to pick up something that um you
know you have an affinity towards I
think it's also totally fine to be like
hey look at all of these jobs in Java I
don't think Java is going away or at
least jvm based languages and so I think
it's totally okay to be like well I'm
going to become an expert in Java that's
not very sexy right now but that's a
totally fine reason so however you get
there my advice is just just go deep
right people will be like okay cool well
I'm going to do a Java tutorial and then
I think an example of going deep is just
being like Oh what's going on in this
virtual machine what are virtual
machines right um what does it what does
it mean to tune a garbage collector and
we can get into a debate about whether
you're going to shoot yourself in the
foot with you know trying to tweak your
jav a garbage collection but if you are
willing to pop the hood on that and then
sort of like take a look at what's going
on in there that's a sort of thing that
nobody can stop you right like you can
just you can just try to go deep Steve
said to go deep so I'm going as deep as
I can till you get to the ones and the
zeros that are flowing through on that
bus right like that is the thing that is
rare last thing on this topic of um you
know breaking in recently Zuck he had
this uh quote he said on an interview
that you know the capabilities of AI in
this year will be able to produce
mid-level engineer code um already do
you think that Junior Engineers are are
screwed then because of that I think
it's super interesting maybe you should
tell me you're the one that works at
meta right but I'll I'll say this Folks
at the CEO
level you know they can they're very
high performing their job is to look
into the future but they tend to make
predictions that
are they're not exaggerated but they
tend to they tend to make things like
the timeline for which things happen
they tend to undershoot that and then um
they tend to overshoot in ability but
the idea is that the vision exists and
you work towards it the fact that he
says he equivocates or at least he's
hedging he he's saying mid-level
Engineers later this year if that was
actually already there he would have
said senior staff level Engineers or 10x
Engineers by tomorrow right the fact
that he's pushing that out makes me
think that the actual Implement like the
rollout of a mid-level AI bot within
meta is a little it's a little further
away because his job is to move the
goalposts just a little further than
where we're at and so I so I have a
little bit of Doubt there now if you
want to talk about you know AI taking
over some tasks yes absolutely they
should you know I think when I was
coming up as a mid and Senior oh code
generation look at these annotations we
can put lombok in our code you don't
have to write Getters and Setters um
there were there was you know I have a
lot of familiarity with Java Java is a
very verbose language Oh look The IDE
can help me refactor some code the IDE
can write some boiler plate for me yes
absolutely we should be leveraging tools
to make us more efficient but at this
point I think of uh AI help as an
amplifier if you just go through the
different levels if you're a non- coder
I think that you can go from zero to one
very easily right so we're getting to
the point with products like repet where
a
Soup To Nuts from beginning to end um
but I have my doubts that if the app
doesn't work uh exactly the way that
it's intended um or they're like hey
scale this thing to meta scale like I I
don't think an AI is going to be able to
do that so I think very comfortably
we'll be able to go from zero to one but
I don't think that it will go from like
one to many I think a 1x
engineer is going to definitely turn
into a 10x engineer today with the help
of a I but do I see a zero to 10x
engineer jump like later this year I I
don't see it okay so then I guess moving
into you being at Amazon you went you
went into Amazon you converted to an SD
and then you climbed all the way to
principal uh at Amazon which I know that
last jump is also very notoriously
difficult so you went from sd1 to sd2
sd3 and then principal
um could you walk me through the the
high level maybe just tell me you know
what was the main thing that made the
difference at each level and you know
just like a very concise uh high level
yeah yeah I was able to get you know to
from support engineer sd1 2 and three
around three three and a half years
something like that you know at sd1 I
think it's the real focus is on some
amount of Independence so just
understanding where you fit fit inside
of the software development life cycle
getting to the point where you can take
tasks and see them all the way through
so you've gained a little bit of trust
there and you don't have to be
handheld um I think that's the critical
piece for um for junior level or
sd1 um I think I just want to add a
caveat there which is that doesn't mean
you know everything and that doesn't
mean that you don't ask questions it's
just that you're much more comfortable
asking a question if you're stuck you're
much more comfortable surfacing an issue
there's some folks that have this idea
that at sd1 or or at any level that you
are completely self-contained so
self-contained is not the same thing as
uh being independent well one of the
common words that he for that first
promo is like doing things independently
without guidance some people interpret
that as I'm not going to ask for help
and I got to do it all myself which is
obviously not right but you need to know
how to unblock yourself so makes sense
and it's also Insidious in the sense
that it's it's not just not right so
that it will hold you back for longer
but it actually turns into a performance
issue if you're hiding the fact that
you're you know not able to perform or
you don't know anything if you're hiding
progress because you're unsure about
yourself and you sort of beat yourself
up that you should know this thing and
you know suppose you have a task and it
should take two weeks and then you're
like hey everything everything's on
track everything's on track and then the
Thursday before you're like I've been
blocked this whole time that's a
performance issue right and so um you
know there's a there's a difference
between oh it's just going to take you
longer to get there to something that's
actually detrial to get to the next
level um I think for
sd2 the the word that pops into my head
the most is ownership and so you know
you are an active participant in s
development life cycle you're much more
of a steward of say your team's
codebase and I I just sort of think
about it like you know hey you're
littering don't Litter here like and
then maybe picking up some of the trash
um that trash being Tech Deb not actual
trash in the code you know being able to
get you know you're now you're able to
leverage this Independence and to start
to make a contribution to the team's
code base that's a little bit larger
right so basically every step up with
sde is kind of an argument that you
deserve more scope and so the the scope
of an sd2 or mid-level engineer
is you know at the team level right you
understand your team's code base you
know you understand its weaknesses its
strengths you can start to you know make
suggestions about where it's going to be
at Amazon we have an operational culture
and so you know you you're on call you
know how things break you might have
some ideas about how to fix some of
these things and so I you know it's it's
a very you know meat and potato sort of
role and you know this this is what you
need to go from two to three yeah I'm
just talking about two oh this is table
Stakes for yeah I think it's
expectations for at least this is my
conception of it right M and there's an
eternal debate at Amazon about whether
the sd2 or mid-level role is a terminal
position or not can you retire as an sd2
the level granularity at Amazon is such
that I think S2 is a very wide band so I
think at the upper levels of S2 a lot of
those folks are senior engineers at
other companies um even within big Tech
not just you know oh they a senior
engineer um at a a smaller company or a
startup I think they're you're you're
pretty strong um as an sd2 at Amazon
just because the granularity for levels
at Amazon is so
terrible and um so I I tend to to bias
towards like yeah actually at
sd2 you're uh that could be a terminal
level right now I don't advise that
people think of it as a terminal level
but it's just a reflection of you know
how much scope I think an sd2 at Amazon
can can actually deliver against so
there isn't an up and out policy like if
you were a manager at Amazon and you had
someone that says Hey I want to just
stay at at you know
sd2 um is that okay or would they get
fired in Amazon's culture eventually so
and it might have changed you know it's
been it's been close to a year since
I've been gone so I say we a lot as
though I still work there I'm still
trying to train myself I don't work at
Amazon yeah um so uh it's definitely up
and out at sd1 yeah and so if you've
been at sd1 for more than 2 years you
know it's it's kind of like H this is is
there formal formal like you know 24
months and then they start managing out
or it's a feel thing I believe it's a
it's a strong it's a progressively
stronger Guidance the longer that you've
been there but it's not a 20 36 months
and then you're out sort of thing yeah
yeah um I think for sd2 it's a much more
interesting conversation I think that
will depend on
the where the upper management you know
for that particular individual where
they land on whether S2 is a terminal
level or not MH um and so if you happen
to get a manager that's basically like
no you've been there for 10 years you
should be a three um if you happen to to
get that person um then I I think it
might be might be bad news for you and
you know with the recent news about meta
a lot of people are likening or they're
worried that meta would turn into Amazon
because Amazon's famous for a culture of
intense performance and cutting people
who aren't making it um from yeah from
your time at Amazon I'm kind of curious
maybe you can give us the the the juicy
details like how many people are
expected to be cut in Amazon typically
like cuz you were there for so many
years is it you know some percentage per
year or is it a to the manager's
discretion how does that work what I can
say so I won't give an exact number uh
what I can say is that guidance you know
suppose it was five or 6% you know for
an organization that number used to be a
recommendation it would it would be kind
of a soft one hey we need to manage out
x% of folks over the course of a year um
I think in the past couple of years that
has turned into a much
more um it's turned from guidance to
much more of a mandate I think coupled
with the fact that up until recently
they weren't doing backfills for folks
there was this sort of like hey keep on
running cuz this thing's chasing you
right from the back yeah I don't think
that was necessarily healthy yeah and
you know if I were to be quite honest I
I consider myself a high performer and
so if you're a high performer you don't
have to think about that stuff and you
know as much as I'd like to be
empathetic about about it and you know
I've been around some of these decisions
and meetings and stuff like that um if
you're down it's I it's hard for me to
to speak about what it's actually like
to to to feel like your job may be at
stake right and so you know I I think a
lot of what I would tell you is is just
kind of cold and numbers based there are
real people here right if you you know
getting fired from a job is
you know that's a that's a very that's a
highly emotional psychological thing
right so I just want to make sure that I
I I bring that up maybe I'll say this
and this is this is sort of how I I
guided other folks and other managers
when they're asking me hey how do I how
do I think about this the way to think
about it
is 5% suppose that was the number right
so that's one in 20
people right and so just just take a
population of 20 people
and I think there's a distribution there
and the people on the left hand side of
that
distribution in regular years where
there are backfills I think
that I think that they're not they're
not having a good time with Amazon's
culture right they're not thriving
almost by definition right we're just
going to say hey everything on the
left-and side is um people aren't aren't
having a great time and so I think it's
almost a relief that there's a way to
sort of like leave a situation like that
what's what's the
alternative they
stay and somebody that's not having a
great time in Amazon's culture which you
know it's it's it doesn't have a great
reputation part of me is like oh that's
kind of nice that you know um it's kind
of a blessing in
disguise right that we would move them
out now without backfills that's where I
start to get a little
uncomfortable because in BAS basically
any other year that they would be at
Amazon they would be totally fine and I
think even people you know that are sort
of left shifted but in that main part of
the distribution I think they're great
um so that's where I start to go like
this is not this is not something that
um I really agree with you're saying
because it starts to cannibalize people
who are they're doing good but now we're
forced to yeah stack ring people that
were good so suppose you had a 6% amount
of folks that were let go and that was a
hard thing and so you did all of the
very tough work to identify those folks
and have them move out and now you need
to do 6% of those folks that remain and
then you need to do 6% of those folks
that remain and so I it's not 18% you
know I don't I can't do that math but
now we're starting to talk talk about
people that are very close to the mid
point they're operating at a high level
and in any other year they'd be totally
fine um but now they're not and so you
know I I I have colleagues that were let
go recently and he just kind of blows my
mind that they would be they would be
let go and so I think the most amount of
impact will come from folks that um say
middle
management where okay okay well there's
four middle managers within the subor
right here the bottom 6% like 6% doesn't
even make sense when you're talking
about four people or eight people right
and so I I was very surprised by some of
the people that were let go recently so
you said when in the past I guess as a
principal engineer once you get higher
up you were privy to some of the
conversations where people are being
discussed if they're getting managed out
what what happens in those conversations
how does a high level IC like you
participate yeah you start getting
pulled in when you're a senior engineer
and you definitely get pulled in when
you're L7 or above those meetings are
terrible right um they're like three
days long and you're locked up in a room
and you're just sitting there talking
about people and people you start to
lose the humanity you just start to
think of them in terms of you know the
measurables right and and the feedback
from other folks um I won't go into the
specific process
um but what I will say
is it's not a linear
algorithm um I think in a in a perfect
world you would just go through
everybody in the org and then you would
you would have equal amount of time to
talk about them and their strengths and
their
weaknesses typically you just talk about
the edges um and that's not a reflection
of you know the people that are making
the decisions and whether that's poor or
not it's just it's the math there are
just too many people
and so the the conversation tends to go
to either side and
um yeah it's it's just it's not my
favorite time of year yeah no definitely
it sounds intense especially if they cut
out some low performers and then the
next iteration is like people where you
objectively look at them go oh they're
yeah they're solid but you need to Fork
over some more people now if you want to
talk about meta I think meta is on a
hiring spree if I'm if I'm not mistaken
think you know if uh if your fearless
leader is saying Hey low performers are
leaving and it's say at a 5% number I
think that's the number that's been
floated around
um I I just have a sense that those
folks are probably not having a good
time at meta right
now right um do that everybody no but I
would say the the vast majority of folks
there um if you're talking about one in
20 people 20 random people at meta there
there's probably somebody that's
struggling especially when you start
multiplying that out across a large
population so because the inflow is much
larger than the outflow I wouldn't be
too worried sounds like across big Tech
there's this increased intensity and uh
historically Amazon has been the one
that's always had this level of
increased intensity or at least this
this process of like let's manage out
the low performers quickly and let's
let's just factor that into our
processes given that you've been in a
lot of those performance conversations
do you have any advice for the people
who are on the border where you know if
this is a how we're going to be
operating in the future people who are
kind of just meeting expectations what
is the things that protects you uh in
those
conversations um that they could do for
this coming year to to be safe I think
it's just that if you meet expectations
if you solidly meet expectations if
everybody across the organization met
expectations I don't think you have a 5%
stack ranking like removing folks from
the
system right and so you know I I don't
think that people that are and I bristle
a bit at the low performer
label I just I just again I think of it
as like the culture is not working out
there is a mismatch between me and the
ambient environment at any particular
company I don't think it's a low perform
you know how hard it is to get a an
offer at
meta like you are not a um low performer
yeah right you you have to be driven
there is a song and dance that you need
to that you need to perform under
pressure in front of somebody like you
go and take a Le code hard and you have
to go look at some you know you have to
coat it in front of some SD that's like
got a bad expression on their face like
you are more than qualified your
smart as hell and now you're working at
a company
and maybe you thought it was something
different than what it actually was what
I would say is I don't think these low
performers these so-called low
performers they should try to become
High
performers right I
think by focusing on trying to be a high
performer or focusing on trying to get
to the next
level there's usually a reason why
you're considered you're labeled that
way and so try to figure out what is
that Dimension that you're being judged
and measured against that's that's
holding you back from meeting
expectations so I think you need to
crawl before you walk before you run
what is that thing that they're judging
you on and then I think you should be
real with your manager and you should
say hey I just wanted to check in am I
meeting expectations and if I'm
not then like let's let's do a
preemptive plan right so pip stands for
performance Improvement plan can you do
a pre tip can you can you proactively
put together a plan to get you to a spot
where you're going to be safe that's
what I would that's what I would
recommend just be proactive about growth
to get back to the median asking your
manager for a proactive pip is I would
maybe not use those words that's
hilarious um okay so it sounds like I
mean obviously meet expectations work
with your manager well I don't think
it's obvious I don't I actually if you
if you took a Sur
of software developers and you asked
them have you used these words with your
manager suppose you're my manager yeah
hey Ryan um you know I just started here
at meta um I just wanted to get a sense
of what my your expectations of me what
are those right have they have you
explicitly asked about expectations with
your manager I think like 25% of of
people have actually done that I think
most people are trying to guess
at what those expectations are and so I
think that would be my first bit of
advice is just like straight up ask what
expectations are and then ask if you're
meeting them or not right that would go
so far definitely yeah that makes a lot
of sense I think most people all right I
don't know if it's um being shy or or
what but feel like most ic's don't
directly talk to their manager and say I
want this or you know how do I meet
expectations how do I get promoted
kind of just do the work and do it well
and hope that things go go well well
obviously there's going to be an answer
yeah and so it's like hey Ryan Ryan
what's your expectation of me and am I
meeting it it's like no Steve you are
not meeting expectations and um it's
starting to become a problem even that
is a better situation than not knowing
oh yeah for sure right and so um there's
a mutual friend of ours Rahul Pandy from
Tero yeah yeah I stole this saying from
him and I don't know if he stole it from
somebody else that worked at meta but
it's basically like um bad news that's
delivered early is just
news right right bad news that's
delivered late is terrible news yeah so
the the you know so if you are asking
about expectations and it's early in
your career it's early in cycle you know
and they're like hey this is a problem
well now you've surfaced the issue
and you have a like you have a Fighting
Chance of actually addressing it if you
are like hey what's up with my
expectations oh it's really bad and it's
December right so the month's preceding
performance review you're not in a good
spot yeah right and so I I just
encourage people to deliver or try to
find as much bad news as early as
possible for your principal promo I
think a lot of it comes down to
having the opportunity and then
delivering but I it's it's interesting
to dig into how you got the opportunity
to even deliver on principal scope so
kind of curious can you tell the story
about how you got that so I was reorg
back into Prime video and so the
previous team to that was a team that I
cared deeply about it was called Amazon
tickets we sold tickets like Ticket
Master Built a bunch of really awesome
Tech um a ton of
patents um I love music I love going to
live shows and so I was like oh this is
great they spun that business down and
they reorg that whole team into Prime
videoo and
um basically the 30 or 40 devs that were
in that
organization they kind of just scattered
into the wind right and um I was I had a
bad taste in my MTH and so I was and I
didn't want to talk to any of their team
so I was basically like okay well what
do I have here what what they had was a
a team that was focused on delivering
live sports on the Prime video
platform and uh I'm a big sports fan as
well and so I was like okay well this is
interesting and then I looked around I
was like oh there's a bunch of principal
Engineers here okay so cool I can I can
learn about what's going on there and um
there is this really big need that was
there um just the the catalog work
and you know I I just made a decision
about whether I wanted to pick it up or
not right um and I decided to it was
just in reality much larger than any
other project that I had ever done I
wouldn't say it would it landed on my
lap I it was a combination of staying
and then sort of saying okay well if I
stay I need to do this I see so it's
some scope that
principal Engineers were aware of needed
to be done was particularly difficult it
was it was just sitting there for
someone to take it on yeah you took the
initiative say all right I'm going to
take it and stay on this team and then
you delivered on it yeah it's you know
the way that the principles were
organized back then it's changed now but
essentially the principles were assigned
to different areas say like playback or
clients or catalog or wherever they were
and the work that needs to be done
was in the gaps between those or so it
had to be an end to-end
solution and so even though the the the
thrust the main thrust of the work was
in these sort of centralized services
and
so that's why you know nobody none of
the other principles had done it because
they were kind of they were doing all of
this other stuff that was necessary for
us to deliver okay so that that makes a
lot sense too cuz I imagine also if you
delivered on that so each principal to
each um I guess Central vertical and
you're delivering some glue work um if
you did that job really well not only is
the scope huge but also these principal
Engineers are you know they're going to
have context on your work and speak to
your packet and be champions for you so
I'm sure that was helpful too A lot of
people they say getting to principle
Amazon is so difficult people don't even
recommend doing it you know there's all
this job hop advice
so what is the thing that usually blocks
people from going from senior to
principal at Amazon there's a lot of
reasons um I
think just to back up a little bit I am
of the impression that Amazon just
skipped a level so they should just
insert a staff level uh staff
level they could do that right now
basically they would say okay well
everybody that's principal will'll call
you principls shove staff in there and
then just say hey for you know for the
really high performing S3s we're just
going to move you there preemptively and
that would be so great but I think the
big problem is that you're essentially
jumping two levels uh for that
particular promotion and
so the the big thing that's holding them
back is that you need to jump two levels
right so there's there's basically
double the amount of criteria to get to
that next level and I think it's kind of
impossible to um exhibit all of the
moving to criteria for principal in a
year so if you think you're ready hey
I'm a senior engineer I've been doing
really well I'm going to make a big
push I think it's like it's it's because
the job is so different because now
you're influencing multiple
teams it's very difficult to find the
opportunity and then also be able to
perform at a level where people would
consider you the next level 12 18 months
and so what ends up happening for you
know the the failure mode that I see the
most is they think they're ready they
will make a push they will get a
rejection and they will get some amount
of
feedback
and then what they'll do is they'll you
know they'll just go back to their
strengths and then they'll continue to
work on their they might like address
one or two of these pieces of feedback
but it just takes so long to um to close
one of these
cycles and so a lot of people give up I
I know so many folks that you know went
to meta and they're they're thri or they
went to Google absolutely thriving right
now senior staff
E8 you know principal at Google which is
you know two levels past staff and uh in
and one level above senior staff they're
doing awesome they just couldn't make
that jump right from sd3 to principal
and so it it turns into this thing where
I think there's this 2-year sliding
window of where you kind of have to pack
in basically a new job you have to
basically be doing two jobs because
there's a there's an anti- pattern where
you just stop doing all the things that
you need to do for sd3 and you just
focus on the principal level stuff and
then performance review time comes
around and then they're like uh you're
actually low performance at sd3 even
though you're a high performer doing
principal level things H how's that
possible like what are those two jobs
and how are they so different well the
reason it's possible is because um
performance and promotion are decoupled
two different processes what's the
performance process at Amazon
performance process is you know uh
yearly and then you know every six
months there's a smaller version of that
and then the promotion process is
depends on the level so it could be
quarterly or it could be every six
months so they might line up generally
but the idea is that there's not a
dependency on one with the other and so
if you're trying to make a big push for
a promotion and you're doing all this
principal stuff and then you know then
it's so here's here's a big example
senior Engineers need to code right
that's a that's a very important thing
that they
do and um principles are also expected
to code but not as large of a
contribution generally like Direct
contribu ution is not rare but it just
that needs to be balanced with their
other obligations so they might be a
sponsor of a project or they might be
acting as a back stop or they might be
acting as a catalyst or an evangelist
for a particular
initiative and so you know those
roles they are pan team right so it's
it's cross functional teams there might
be product teams there might be five Dev
teams these Dev teams
maybe spanning multiple organizations
you might act like a TPM I was accused
of that in one of my um promotion
assessments uh it's kind of hard to
figure out whether Steve's an SD or a
TPM kind of took offense to that I'm
like are are you kidding me dude and and
you know one of them came back like hey
you need to code more and I'm like I
have checked in so many lines of code
and so okay well I there's some sporadic
you know six months where I didn't code
a lot it's like I didn't get any credit
for time served I see okay so they
looked at the code delivered in those
six months when you're going for
principal they looked at it not a lot of
code and so they said okay we're
blocking you because you're not doing
the senior job yeah but principal was
good because you were doing all the
cross functional yeah and so then it got
kicked so then it's like okay well now
I'll go code right and they'll be like
oh it's been you know it's been a long
time since he's been on call he's not on
the day-to-day operations for an
individual team it's like I've been you
know I I was there for 18 years I have
been on
call longer than Pro like time on call
longer than most people's careers at
Amazon by far I've probably been on call
like four years continuously yeah and so
you get feedback like that and you're
just like this like I'm battling the
process now right and so to to be quite
honest I was promoted in
2020 um and I thought I was ready at
2016 so you know I I was promoted to
senior in 2012 so it took 8 years to get
there I thought I was there in 2016 and
four years and you went for promo every
year and they gave you like this TPM
feedback or other yeah there was there
were a number of obstacles but you know
they changed the process three times
during that four year span um I I just
to be honest I probably hadn't generated
evidence that I was operating at that
level that's not to say that I didn't
have the ability but you need to
generate this tangible evidence that
goes into your packet so I wasn't quite
there yet you need the support of your
manager and so there was a there was a
number of reasons why I wasn't able to
get there um but a lot of it was just
battling the process itself I don't
think I necessarily up leveled myself I
think I just became an expert in the
process of getting promoted and so what
did you learn from becoming an expert of
that promo process for senior 2 yeah I
you know I I think about it and like is
that a useful skill yeah I think so I
think it's useful for people that are in
Amazon I learned a couple of things so
the big ones are don't wait to start I
think a lot of people postpone
themselves and so they're like oh well
after this big project
lands that's when I'll get my packet
together but the project Landing may not
be the thing that that you would be
rejected for and so I'm a big proponent
of being kind of impatient and putting
your packet in early and then getting
that actual feedback about where the
gaps are so that's one failure pattern I
think the other is you
know you do get some amount of credit
for strengths in your promo packet and
so suppose your strengths are you know
he's a great
communicator um very data driven he does
a lot of you know he's a Str there's a
strength with
interviewing um great coder cool uh
feedback oh well he's not scaling
through others uh he could be a better
Mentor um he doesn't communicate upward
very well to directors or
VPS um so let's work on that you don't
really have to put so much emphasis on
the strengths just make sure that they
don't regress and turn into problems but
I think you can just focus on the delta
because that's what the promo panel is
going to do when you're you know we try
to make the the promo packet sticky to a
particular set of individuals and so
it's like okay well Ryan you know
rejected you get the big red Stamper
thing on a piece of paper and you know
six months later it's like oh Ryan he's
not promoted yet okay like let's dig in
again with humans just like the talent
review
process you're you're going to look at
the Delta you're going to look at the
outliers right and so you're going to be
like okay well what changed right and
just like let's look at the like the
evidence that's there and so if you're
able to really focus in on the the areas
for growth the places where there aren't
as many data points then uh I think
you'll be pretty successful when you get
that packet back you're saying there's
the strengths and then there's things
that blocked it and you're saying
strengths they're good don't you don't
need to worry about those just focus on
on the weaknesses and closing those gaps
I would just say prioritize the
weaknesses and gaps and you just I think
about it like uh you're in a kitchen
with a lot of pots and pans everywhere
it's like your strengths you can put
that on the back burner mhh right but um
you know this uh this risoto like you're
going to sit here and make sure that the
risoto is good right it's like it's like
you're adding broth you you just can't
you have to make sure that you got that
right and so you said you were at Amazon
for 18 years their Amazon's culture is
very specific they have the leadership
principles it's its own yeah culture
what's your favorite parts of Amazon
culture and then we'll also talk about
the worst Parts too the worst Parts is
it you know I think there's some amount
of Stockholm syndrome for me being there
for so long I'm drinking the Kool-Aid
you know I still say I we even though
it's been a while since I work what's
your favorite Kool-Aid then well I just
the big thing is uh customer obsession
oh yeah I I think especially when Bezos
was there
um nobody ever gave uh lip service to
the customer experience that was the
highest
priority from interns to
VPS you were always going to be doing
the right thing if you had the customer
in mind absolutely
100% um and I just I think that's a
great North
Star and so you know I think if you
chase profits or you focus on
competitors or you know there's a lot of
other trappings that are there you might
optimize for the wrong thing right if
you optimize for shortterm next quarter
profits it's going to bite you in the
long run um if you optimize for you know
if you're just sort of chasing that's
another problem right and so if you if
you actually work backward from the
customer you know Jeff Bezos has that
saying they're like hey long-term
profits and and customers those are the
same thing there's no difference there I
think that's wonderful another thing
that I
absolutely I think is a superpower for
Amazon is their writing culture you know
I think um the ability to write a
six-page doc that was that was
accelerated by the fact that I have a
writing degree and so I didn't realize
that I had the precursor to a
superpower um when I joined I I was
worried about like learning Java right
or or learning how to to deploy to
man I wish people would have a college
class to figure out how to like send an
email or to be clear about like the work
that's in front of them and so what
comes with a a wonderful writing culture
is a wonderful reading culture like we
literally will spend the first 30
minutes of a meeting reading the
document and then we will have a
discussion afterwards there's no this
never works it's like oh I sent you the
document
so after you've read the document we're
all going to get in the no nobody does
that right like they should it's like a
best intention sort of thing right but
the fact that you're forced to read it
at the same time and everybody's just
sort of fast forwarded to the same place
and then you can have a discussion like
that's actually super powerful so if
someone was on boarding to Amazon they
really want to make sure they hit the
ground running and plug into the
culture would you say that's one of the
most important things yeah if if they if
they are curious about how we know we're
doing right by the
customer yeah I think that's a you if
you have a curiosity about that you will
do you will do really well um the
writing culture I think that's just the
medium by which we express our ideas
that's
learnable um that's something that I
wouldn't necessarily focus on before you
joined you said you're drinking the
Kool-Aid but there's got to be something
that you don't like about Amazon culture
what would be the number one thing
uh I know mine what's that I remember
this was uh this was like a joke among
my friends and I Amazon I there's the
leadership principles right and you know
there a list of what 11 or 12 things
that yeah everyone's kind of basing
everything off of and there's one there
that was just like the recurring inside
joke among our friend group which was
frugality basically anything anytime
something was crappy or cheap or
whatever we would just say oh frugality
so you know no free food no uh there was
some other things too like a hardware
wasn't particularly good or yeah you
know I think free food that's a
perk if if a company doesn't provide you
food like that doesn't mean it's a bad
company so it's it's it's great on the
upside but I don't think there's it says
very much on the other side I do think
think you know frugality uh we we have a
term called being Frid where you are
right so Frugal that it's kind of stupid
I had to beg borrow and plead for
Hardware right like I'm I'm trying to
get a trying to get a MacBook Pro with
like some Ram so that it doesn't like
like the fan doesn't overheat when I'm
running like building my code it's
like if you're going to hire you know
tens of thousands of software developers
you won't like get them a computer that
work now I'm not saying like I need the
top-of-the-line thing I just I just need
a computer I'm a software developer give
me a you know give me a computer that
works you know when intern season would
come and then the interns would leave
and then the vultures would come to try
to steal the
monitors right and so it's just like you
know it just it just reminds me of like
Oliver Twist like you know it's like
more please it's like you just want a
little bit more
GRL yeah one thing that I wanted to dig
into uh and I guess this is switching to
another topic is in your time at Amazon
you had 17 managers over 18
years so you've seen a lot when it comes
to managers what was it that made your
best manager the best manager out of 17
I think I had more than 17 managers
actually really yeah okay than it was in
the 20s last time I checked I took a
screenshot of my phone tool you know I
think a lot about this you know uh
sometimes people would complain about a
micromanager but there's a class of of
folks that kind of like a micromanager
like they they kind of need to be led
they kind of need things broken down for
them I do think that a lot of what makes
a good manager is personal the ones that
I resonated with um they tended to be
principles based right so not just the
leadership principle stuff but like the
way that they operated um they sort of
reasoned through you think of these
principles as
axioms and um you know so you fix
certain things and and those things have
implications and so the best managers I
think they fixed customer Obsession they
fixed uh things that I value like sort
of thinking ahead in the future so they
were maybe willing to entertain some you
know some stuff that in the short term
like a hack but it was always within the
context of like what should we do what's
the right thing to do in the future okay
so like let's made a tradeoff for that
instead of you know maybe some managers
that I didn't like are folks that are
maybe too delivery oriented right so
it's just a constant Death March it's
about delivery it's about near-term
delivery um so folks that kind of
thought a little bit ahead in the future
and um were maybe not so constrained by
what we had in front of us I see and
then what about the worst manager you
had out of 20 something managers yeah I
don't want to name names or anything but
um you know sometimes I think about how
did we get
here right and so like we live in a in a
moment right now and so I'm talking to
you and so I I I can see it you know a
year ago he was here and a year before
that he was here and I I can kind of see
the progression of how you get from you
know maybe a university student at
UCLA to where you are right now like
that aggression makes sense I think some
people that I worked with you're like
how did you get
here like it's it's sort of like the
Silicon Valley thing I forget the name
of the guy that uh bigh head yeah yeah
it had to have been some sort of big
head
scenario where you know he fell up right
luck happened and everything just sort
of landed in their lap so you know um I
think the worst managers I had would be
combination of like not my style right
so again you know micromanager one
person is a really caring and engaged
manager to another person and then um
just a little bit of like WTF like how
did you get here I thought that the
whole performance and promotion process
and the hiring process was supposed to
filter a certain set of folks out and
here we are at the end of each interview
I like to go over just general
reflections of people um kind of looking
over the career what are the things that
you learned and and various other things
um one thing that I'm curious about
because you were at Amazon for 18 years
and in this industry that is
extraordinary people already call me
fossil for being at meta for greater
than four or five years so you know what
kept you at Amazon so long I think that
you know we had talked about the number
of managers that I had reported
to um
I had many careers many many careers at
Amazon right so I worked on the first
Kindle and I worked on the precursor to
Prime video before I went back to Prime
video I and I worked on in payments so
you know I think the fact that Amazon
does so many different things um has
allowed me to work on a variety of
different things you know and didn't
feel like I've been on one team it's not
like I worked in the accounting
department for 25 years and they handed
me a gold watch right um and so you know
there's a there's a VP I think he's
still a VP at in advertising Paul cotus
he he told me one day he said I've never
switched
teams wow right like Amazon just kind of
you know refactored itself around him
until he was BP of ads right and so
great guy and so um you know I don't
think it's gets to that extreme but um
you know I had a wide variety of
experiences there and so it does it
doesn't feel like one 18-year contiguous
sort of experience so it sounds like you
were still challenged learning I think
when I was at Amazon for my short
stunt it was difficult for me to not
have wandering eyes because there were
these other hot companies recruiters
were messaging me and you know I was
just seeing that oh maybe I can get more
somewhere else
um did did you ever consider leaving
Amazon yeah yeah absolutely I think
um you know especially early career it
makes a lot of sense to jump
companies uh you know everybody hears
the the common advice it's like hey you
want to maximize your total comp you
should be job hopping I think that works
until you get to the equivalent of
senior after that I think you know
you're an outlier here but I think after
that it makes sense to put Roots down
right the the levels that at the highest
levels I I don't think you're going to
find a lot of distinguished Engineers or
principal Engineers or staff senior
staff Engineers that haven't been on the
team like the like the jump the thing
that got them to that level I think you
what you'll find is that you know there
there was like five years you know at
least like at least three but more like
five or so where they really stayed on
the same team on the same problem right
right and so you know I think if you
want to min max it what I would say is
you know job hop every two years till
you get to to Mid maybe a little bit
before and then go to um you know and
then try to put Roots down if you want
to become a highle tech IC for me I
think that because I was able to to go
to different teams and you know because
I don't have that computer science
background I think staying put made a
ton of sense because I feel like I
didn't there was so much to learn right
you know there was so many there was so
much code that you had access to there
were all of these wikis you know these
internal videos and so I felt like I
could still grow in the ways that I
wanted to by staying at Amazon I
remember even when I was at Amazon the
stock was climbing like crazy did you
have any years where you were just super
overcome ated and if so how much were
you making in that year so here's the
thing
I I would uh you know I I was basically
divesting and then you know putting
money into other
Investments and I won't say that I
missed a lot of like the Amazon's climb
because a lot of it was was sort of
unvested right
um I don't know I think uh 2020 or
something like that I probably got like
an extra 350k that I didn't
deserve you know just from from the
market returns and and extra rsus that
were given to me um when I left so 2024
I you know if on the on the vesting
schedule that I was on I would have made
750k which is not a lot compared to like
the upper end of the salary ranges but
quite a bit just sort of objectively as
a number to make in the US at this point
in time I decided around I think 2018 or
2019 to to maybe like not divest my
Amazon shares cuz it was always like
you're dumb like you shouldn't put all
of your eggs in one basket but every
time I sold stock just if you just look
at the stock price it was just it was
just the wrong move right and so I was
like I'm done I'm done I'm not going to
keep every single little bit but um I'm
going to keep some and so that turned
out to be okay you said extra Equity did
does Amazon have a uh for high
performers uh like a discretionary
Equity or additional Equity um not that
I know of I think um I compensation is
largely you're talking about like
Refreshers then yeah yeah it's at the
discretion of managers and so you know
one of my one of my best managers he was
basically
like YOLO YOLO he was like I'm out and
so so he hooked me up you know and and
left me go but it's not like these
insane like million-dollar things that I
ever got how how big of a difference to
that it was that 350 Delta oh I see I
see just like that was over four years
or no it was it was just sort of all at
once it just here's
350 okay that's pretty good yeah yeah it
was it was the equivalent of that he was
he was basically on his way out and he
he gave it to me and then he left and
then that appreciated essentially the
next year like immediately so oh that's
amazing it wasn't it wasn't like here's
he didn't write me a check it was just a
combination of the um of sort of getting
an outsized um performance bonus and and
the stock price just doing really well
okay so over the course of your career
18 years at Amazon one thing that I'm
curious is what was your biggest regret
um yeah certain teams I think just just
reading the the the writing on the wall
and making a sober decision about
whether to stay or whether to leave I
think there was a lot of inertia I think
your default mode is to just stay put
for some amount of time and I don't know
if that's useful the uh I guess the
career regret is noticing when you're in
a bad situation or a bad team and just
taking the initiative to change that
situation just leave the regret is just
did you make it a decision or not did
you take in all of the considerations
and then said said okay I am going to
continue to stay it's the deferral of a
decision and so the default becomes just
staying put that's the regret it's just
like just turn it into an explicit
decision and the last question I like to
ask and I ask everyone this question is
if you could go back to you or you just
graduated college you're right about to
enter the industry you could tell
yourself something what would be the
thing that you want to tell yourself um
I think I
think maybe saying something
around people pleasing right um you know
in the the culture that I was raised in
and you know there are these tracks that
you get on and it's like okay we'll do
well in school and then go get a job and
then go get married and like you know
you have this feeling of
being ahead or behind right so that
relative
comparison um but then also after you do
a thing after you make some sort of
achievement you're kind of looking for
to someone else for
validation and
um I don't know if my younger self would
have like listened to be quite honest
with you but you know just if I could
somehow learn this lesson that like the
person that you really need to please is
yourself
like just just being like are is are you
doing what you want to do or are you
doing it because that's the expectation
of somebody else are you climbing the
ladder because you want to get to the
top or are you climbing a ladder because
the ladder was put in front of you just
examining that um that makes sense cool
well thanks so much for your time Steve
I really enjoyed the conversation and uh
yeah I guess now would be the time if we
if you want to shout out anything that
you're working on um I have my uh
YouTube channel it's called a life
engineered um so go and subscribe to
that I have a Weekly Newsletter um that
gets sent out so you know it takes a
long time to make a YouTube video and so
you know if you want more from me the
newsletters there and then if you want
to chat um just join my Discord awesome
cool all right well thanks so much for
your time Steve really appreciate it
absolutely